smokersguide.com 2015-03-21

# Privacy Policy | Smokers Guide info

### Privacy Statement for the Smokers Guide

Smokers Guide has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. This is very important when dealing with the subjects we cover. We respect the fact that many of our viewers may not share our views. We are considerate to the privacy of all our viewers. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website: smokersguide.com

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information.

This site contains links to other sites. Smokers Guide is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. We check all of our links for their general integrity, but we can't be held responsible for sites that are not ours.

Our site uses a Become a Reviewer form to allow viewers to gain access to the rating/review system. We collect visitor's contact information (like their email address), demographic information (like their country, age, or gender) and basic interests (hobbies, leisure activities or areas of expertise). Contact information from the member form is used in-house, to make certain there is no fraudulent use of the system (i.e. "over voting"). The customer's contact information is never used unless a newsletter and/or other type of correspondance is requested by the viewer. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. We use this data to tailor our visitor's experience at our site, showing them content that we think they might be interested in, and displaying the content according to their preferences.

#### Public Forums

This site makes a public forum available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

#### Choice/Opt-Out

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us at the point where we request information about the visitor. This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our service. You can send email to remove@smokersguide.com

#### Correct/Update

This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided. Change reviewer profile.

#### Contacting the Web Site

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact

SGuide   
Postbus 59595  
1040 LB Amsterdam  
The Netherlands  
privacy@smokersguide.com
